Love Comes Softly is a drama, romance, western
film directed by Michael Landon Jr..
Nineteen year old pioneer woman Marty has recently married.
She goes west with her husband Clem, hoping to start a new life.
But Clem unexpectedly dies, and Marty finds herself alone, two months pregnant.
Widower Clark offers her a marriage of convenience: she needs food and
money, and he needs someone to take care of his daughter Missie.
She accepts his proposal as a temporary solution.
Marty Claridge, played by Katherine Heigl.
Clark Davis, played by Dale Midkiff.
Missie Davis, played by Skye McCole Bartusiak.
Ben Graham, played by Corbin Bernsen.
Sarah Graham, played by Theresa Russell.
Aaron Claridge, played by Oliver Macready.
Love Comes Softly is a 2003 made-for-television Christian drama film set in
the 19th century, based on a series of books by Janette Oke.
It originally aired on Hallmark Channel on April 13, 2003.
It was directed by Michael Landon Jr..
It stars Katherine Heigl as a young woman named Marty Claridge
and Dale Midkiff as a widower named Clark Davis.
It is the first in a series of television movies made for Hallmark Channel based on
the books and produced for Hallmark by Larry Levinson Productions.
The order of the films are the 8 originals followed by the 3 prequels:
Love Comes Softly (2003)
Love's Enduring Promise (2004)
Love's Long Journey (2005)
Love's Abiding Joy (2006)
Love's
Unending Legacy (2007)
Love's Unfolding Dream (2007)
Love Takes Wing (2009)
Love Finds a Home (2009)
Love Begins (2011)
Love's Everlasting Courage (2011)
Love's Christmas Journey (2011)
The film explores themes of based on novel or book, widow,
sequel, marriage of convenience, wagon train.
The tone is emotional.